<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/</link><description>Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 09:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure IoT</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iot/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h1 class="relative text-5xl font-semibold leading-tense text-secondary-500 mb-4 -ml-px" id="verify-azure-iot-mq-broker-at-the-edge"><a href="#verify-azure-iot-mq-broker-at-the-edge" class="header-mark" aria-label="Header mark for 'Verify Azure IoT MQ Broker at the Edge'"></a>
  <div id="verify-azure-iot-mq-broker-at-the-edge" class="absolute -top-28"></div>
  Verify Azure IoT MQ Broker at the Edge
</h1>
<p>Since you are <strong>Owner</strong> on the edge machine + Azure, you can confirm the broker and its connectivity from both ends.</p>
<h3 class="text-xl font-bold text-primary-500 leading-tight mb-2" id="a-check-in-iot-operations-portal-gui"><a href="#a-check-in-iot-operations-portal-gui" class="header-mark" aria-label="Header mark for 'a) Check in IoT Operations Portal (GUI)'"></a>
    a) Check in IoT Operations Portal (GUI)
</h3>

<ol>
<li>Go to your instance (Sites → Instances → Your Edge Instance).</li>
<li>In the left menu, select Data flow endpoints.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>
<p>You should see one called MQTT (Default) or similar. This is the built-in broker endpoint.






  
  
    
  


<img src="/posts/azure-iot/img-1f4eb56e-image.png" alt="Image"  />
</p>]]></description></item><item><title>IoT - NodeRED on Arc-Enabled Edge</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</guid><description>Learn how to deploy a fully integrated Node-RED environment inside a K3s Kubernetes cluster on an Azure Arc-connected edge device. This guide walks you through namespace setup, persistent storage, service exposure, and secure access over SSH tunnels. Simulate MQTT and Modbus devices, visualize flows, and forward real-time telemetry to Azure MQ and OPC UA—all without opening firewall ports. Ideal for industrial IoT scenarios needing secure hybrid connectivity and local processing.</description></item><item><title>IoT - Azure Arc Connected K3s</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</guid><description>Transform your on-premises infrastructure into a cloud-integrated powerhouse by combining K3s Kubernetes with Azure Arc on an Ubuntu server. This guide walks you through every step—from deploying K3s and configuring user access to connecting your cluster to Azure Arc, enabling observability with Grafana, and integrating full-scale monitoring with Azure Monitor. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re building edge deployments or hybrid IoT solutions, this tutorial gives you a production-grade environment with the flexibility of the cloud and control of local resources.</description></item><item><title>Using AI to Empower Cloud Architecture and Deployments</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/using-ai-to-empower-cloud-architecture-and-deployments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/using-ai-to-empower-cloud-architecture-and-deployments/</guid><description>The integration of artificial intelligence (AI) into cloud infrastructure is revolutionizing how we manage and deploy cloud resources. AI, now a pivotal component, optimizes the entire lifecycle of cloud architecture, enhancing tasks like deployment, maintenance, and scaling. This article explores the role of AI in empowering cloud architecture and deployments, especially when combined with Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tools like Bicep and Terraform.</description></item><item><title>Bicep - Tags as Parameters</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/bicep-tags-as-parameters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/bicep-tags-as-parameters/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="./cover-b97ceb91.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p><strong>Deploying infrastructure ARM Templates to Azure, but using Tags and their respective value as the parameter configuration settings</strong></p>
<p>In a post earlier, we look at using arm to lookup the value of tags&rsquo; at both the Subscription and Resource Level.</p>
<p>With Bicep this is much easier to understand. This is the same lab configuration as in the original post, but this time to code should be a lot more readable.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Streaming Vinyl On Sonos</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/streaming-vinyl-on-sonos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/streaming-vinyl-on-sonos/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="./cover-e34de797.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p><strong>Mixup some Vyinl Oldies, a little Ice to cast, and a PI for some energy, and your ready to go</strong></p>
<p>A little known trivia - I was once a Disc Jokey, and spent a lot of my youth behind the decks, in clubs around the West Of Ireland. Today, I still am the proud owner of a very large collection of Vynil and CD music, which of course deserves to get a second life with my digital streaming audio system powered by Sonos</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Azure IaC - Tags as Parameters</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iac-tags-as-parameters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iac-tags-as-parameters/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="./cover-855ad084.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Deploying infrastructure ARM Templates to Azure, but using Tags and thier respective value as the parameter configuration settings</p>
<p>In the post, I am going to introduce a concept which will allow you to greatly up your Infrastructure as Code game, by using Azure as a State Machine!</p>
<p>One of the typical challenges when deploying ARM templates, is the sheer number of parameters which we find as a requirement to complete a deployment; which as you will appreciate gets considerably harder as we target many environments.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Change Detection Using Oxidized</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/change-detection-using-oxidized/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/change-detection-using-oxidized/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="./cover-9fdafc82.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Oxidized is a Linux based service which has the ability to monitor a device’s configuration, including software and hardware. Current configuration is backed up from each device and stored to a GIT repository to maintain history of changes.</p>
<p>The process is very simple:</p>
<ol>
<li>Login to each device in the router list router.db,</li>
<li>Run Commands to get the information that will be saved</li>
<li>Clean the output</li>
<li>Commit the Changes to GIT Repository
The tool is coded in <em>Ruby</em>, and implements a Domain Specific Language (DSL) for interaction.</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, there is a Web based User experience included in the solution so we can get a fast overview of the world.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Azure Enterprise Agreement Delegation</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-enterprise-agreement-delegation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-enterprise-agreement-delegation/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="./cover-b0769a29.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Delegating Azure Enterprise Agreement Owner privileges to a Service Principal (SPN)</p>
<p>Under the Enterprise agreement we have some different Persona’s, which have quite different abilities and operations upon which they are permitted to preform.</p>
<p>Before we being the process of delegation, It is important to understand this Hierarchy, so we can correctly proceed with the technical work ahead.</p>
<h1 class="relative text-5xl font-semibold leading-tense text-secondary-500 mb-4 -ml-px" id="enterprise-administrator"><a href="#enterprise-administrator" class="header-mark" aria-label="Header mark for 'Enterprise Administrator'"></a>
  <div id="enterprise-administrator" class="absolute -top-28"></div>
  Enterprise Administrator
</h1>
<p>Has the ability to add additional Enterprise and Department Administrators, Additional this persona can</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Azure IaC - Function Keys</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iac-function-keys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iac-function-keys/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="./cover-459a9864.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p><strong>Retrieve the Function Host Keys while deploying an ARM template</strong></p>
<p>Todays conundrum: As I deploy a new Function Application, I need a simple methodology to retrieve the Host Keys for the function application so that I validate the deployment has been successful; and potentially pass on the key to related services, for example API Management.</p>
<p>As before, I am leveraging templates, and will stay cloud native; this time depending on the functions Output ability to present the keys.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>