<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure IoT Operations on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/series/azure-iot-operations/</link><description>Recent content in Azure IoT Operations on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/series/azure-iot-operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IoT - NodeRED on Arc-Enabled Edge</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</guid><description>Learn how to deploy a fully integrated Node-RED environment inside a K3s Kubernetes cluster on an Azure Arc-connected edge device. This guide walks you through namespace setup, persistent storage, service exposure, and secure access over SSH tunnels. Simulate MQTT and Modbus devices, visualize flows, and forward real-time telemetry to Azure MQ and OPC UA—all without opening firewall ports. Ideal for industrial IoT scenarios needing secure hybrid connectivity and local processing.</description></item><item><title>IoT - Azure Arc Connected K3s</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</guid><description>Transform your on-premises infrastructure into a cloud-integrated powerhouse by combining K3s Kubernetes with Azure Arc on an Ubuntu server. This guide walks you through every step—from deploying K3s and configuring user access to connecting your cluster to Azure Arc, enabling observability with Grafana, and integrating full-scale monitoring with Azure Monitor. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re building edge deployments or hybrid IoT solutions, this tutorial gives you a production-grade environment with the flexibility of the cloud and control of local resources.</description></item></channel></rss>