<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IoT - NodeRED on Arc-Enabled Edge</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</guid><description>Learn how to deploy a fully integrated Node-RED environment inside a K3s Kubernetes cluster on an Azure Arc-connected edge device. This guide walks you through namespace setup, persistent storage, service exposure, and secure access over SSH tunnels. Simulate MQTT and Modbus devices, visualize flows, and forward real-time telemetry to Azure MQ and OPC UA—all without opening firewall ports. Ideal for industrial IoT scenarios needing secure hybrid connectivity and local processing.</description></item><item><title>IoT - Azure Arc Connected K3s</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</guid><description>Transform your on-premises infrastructure into a cloud-integrated powerhouse by combining K3s Kubernetes with Azure Arc on an Ubuntu server. This guide walks you through every step—from deploying K3s and configuring user access to connecting your cluster to Azure Arc, enabling observability with Grafana, and integrating full-scale monitoring with Azure Monitor. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re building edge deployments or hybrid IoT solutions, this tutorial gives you a production-grade environment with the flexibility of the cloud and control of local resources.</description></item><item><title>Streaming Vinyl On Sonos</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/streaming-vinyl-on-sonos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/streaming-vinyl-on-sonos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixup some Vyinl Oldies, a little Ice to cast, and a PI for some energy, and your ready to go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little known trivia - I was once a Disc Jokey, and spent a lot of my youth behind the decks, in clubs around the West Of Ireland. Today, I still am the proud owner of a very large collection of Vynil and CD music, which of course deserves to get a second life with my digital streaming audio system powered by Sonos&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Change Detection Using Oxidized</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/change-detection-using-oxidized/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/change-detection-using-oxidized/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oxidized is a Linux based service which has the ability to monitor a device’s configuration, including software and hardware. Current configuration is backed up from each device and stored to a GIT repository to maintain history of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process is very simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to each device in the router list router.db,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Commands to get the information that will be saved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean the output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit the Changes to GIT Repository
The tool is coded in &lt;em&gt;Ruby&lt;/em&gt;, and implements a Domain Specific Language (DSL) for interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is a Web based User experience included in the solution so we can get a fast overview of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guacamole Azure Appliance</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/guacamole-azure-appliance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/guacamole-azure-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apache Guacamole is a free and open source web application which lets you access your dashboard from anywhere using a modern web browser. It is a clientless remote desktop gateway which only requires Guacamole installed on a server and a web browser supporting HTML5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guacamole is the best way to keep multiple instances accessible over the internet. Once you add an instance to Guacamole, you don’t need to remember the password as it can securely store the credentials. It also lets you share the desktops among other users in a group. Guacamole supports multiple connection methods such as SSH, Telnet, VNC, and RDP.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CBus MQTT Bridge on Raspberry PI</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/cbus-mqtt-bridge-on-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/cbus-mqtt-bridge-on-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Turn back to 2007; My wife and I built our home, integrating many smart technologies, including the Clipsal C-Bus lighting system. This solution is classified as a Prosumer technology, and is designed to integrate into whole house automation systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The C-Bus system implements however a propriatory technology, and utilizes a communication protocol which is not ‘open source’; however, accepting a licence agreement will permit access to this protocol for creating an programming interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing Docker and Compose on Raspbian Buster</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/installing-docker-and-compose-on-raspbian-buster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/installing-docker-and-compose-on-raspbian-buster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Quickly update a new Raspberry Pi, which has an install of Raspbian Buster with Docker and Docker-compose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 class="relative text-5xl font-semibold leading-tense text-secondary-500 mb-4 -ml-px" id="docker"&gt;&lt;a href="#docker" class="header-mark" aria-label="Header mark for 'Docker'"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;div id="docker" class="absolute -top-28"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 Docker
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simple, as the Docker team have done all the work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="code-block highlight is-open show-line-numbers tw-group tw-my-2"&gt;
 &lt;div class="
 code-block-title 
 
 tw-flex 
 tw-flex-row 
 tw-justify-between 
 tw-w-full tw-bg-bgColor-secondary
 "&gt; 

 &lt;div class="code-block-title-bar tw-w-full"&gt;
 &lt;p class="tw-select-none !tw-my-1"&gt;&lt;svg class="icon"
 xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 320 512"&gt;&lt;!-- Font Awesome Free 5.15.4 by @fontawesome - https://fontawesome.com License - https://fontawesome.com/license/free (Icons: CC BY 4.0, Fonts: SIL OFL 1.1, Code: MIT License) --&gt;&lt;path d="M285.476 272.971L91.132 467.314c-9.373 9.373-24.569 9.373-33.941 0l-22.667-22.667c-9.357-9.357-9.375-24.522-.04-33.901L188.505 256 34.484 101.255c-9.335-9.379-9.317-24.544.04-33.901l22.667-22.667c9.373-9.373 24.569-9.373 33.941 0L285.475 239.03c9.373 9.372 9.373 24.568.001 33.941z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;shell&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Waking Deamons</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/waking-deamons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/waking-deamons/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With a multitude of Raspberry PI’s deployed around the house, each taking a dedicated duty in ensuring that services run transparently; It is not uncommon for me to discover the initialization scripts designed to have these services auto start at boot is not working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of this post is a reference for different methods which can be employed to resolve these stubborn daemons; which always are to fond of reappearing after an unplanned outage; or what is more commonly referred to as a Power Failure!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>