<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bicep on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/tags/bicep/</link><description>Recent content in Bicep on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/tags/bicep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using AI to Empower Cloud Architecture and Deployments</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/using-ai-to-empower-cloud-architecture-and-deployments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/using-ai-to-empower-cloud-architecture-and-deployments/</guid><description>The integration of artificial intelligence (AI) into cloud infrastructure is revolutionizing how we manage and deploy cloud resources. AI, now a pivotal component, optimizes the entire lifecycle of cloud architecture, enhancing tasks like deployment, maintenance, and scaling. This article explores the role of AI in empowering cloud architecture and deployments, especially when combined with Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tools like Bicep and Terraform.</description></item><item><title>Bicep - Tags as Parameters</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/bicep-tags-as-parameters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/bicep-tags-as-parameters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploying infrastructure ARM Templates to Azure, but using Tags and their respective value as the parameter configuration settings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a post earlier, we look at using arm to lookup the value of tags&amp;rsquo; at both the Subscription and Resource Level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Bicep this is much easier to understand. This is the same lab configuration as in the original post, but this time to code should be a lot more readable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azure IaC - Appending Tags</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iac-appending-tags/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/posts/azure-iac-appending-tags/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamically appending Tags to our ARM template with the union function&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todays conundrum: As I am leveraging templates, there will always be some standard tags I require to implement within the template, but I also require to provide additional tags as a parameter to be appended with the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My objective is to set up tags within an ARM template in accordance with good governance and the Cloud adoption framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>