<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSG on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/tags/ssg/</link><description>Recent content in SSG on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 15:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/tags/ssg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing Comments on a Static Site</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/implementing-comments-on-a-static-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/implementing-comments-on-a-static-site/</guid><description>&lt;p>At this point we are almost ready to go live with our site, however, one of the cornerstones to growing and sharing is communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="wordpress">Wordpress&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In the world of Wordpress, this was a standard core feature, which leveraged the fact that the pages were rendered on demand from a backend database. In this scenario, the same approach is offered to maintain a commenting platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, as I noted earlier; given that Wordpress powers a very large portion of the blogging surface of the internet; it is an obvious target for hacking, just refer to the CVS database for a glimpse of what this looks like in reality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using pipelines for flow static site content between markdown and foundation</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/using-pipelines-for-flow-static-site-content-between-markdown-and-foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/using-pipelines-for-flow-static-site-content-between-markdown-and-foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the heavy lifting done in creating the site building mechanics and a solid foundation to build and share upon; our final objective is to automate the process of connecting these two stages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="release-pipeline">Release Pipeline&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Technically the goal we are speaking about is the &lt;strong>Release Pipeline&lt;/strong> which will take the artefact &lt;em>(our site .ZIP file)&lt;/em> that we created in the &lt;strong>Build Pipeline&lt;/strong> in our previous topic &lt;a href="https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/Building-The-Site/">Constructing a new Home with Jekyll and Azure DevOps&lt;/a>; and publish this to our storage account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laying the foundation in Azure for a Static Site</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/laying-the-foundation-in-azure-for-a-static-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/laying-the-foundation-in-azure-for-a-static-site/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hosting my site on Wordpress was not super complex; I leveraged the Azure PaaS Services for Web Apps, and orginally the 3rd party support for hosted MySQL database’s. Once I was up and running I quickly realised that all media hosted on the site were landing on the webserver, so a plugin from its marketplace offered the ability to relocate the media to an Azure Blob; offloading some of the challanges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constructing a new Home with Jekyll and Azure DevOps</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/constructing-a-new-home-with-jekyll-and-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/constructing-a-new-home-with-jekyll-and-azure-devops/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the unspoken truths behind the lack of posts in recent history was due to a few bugs, which in the end resulted in an experience where from home it appeared that any new content was published and working; but outside this fortress in the real world, there was a large silence echoing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really only discovered this issue in May of this year, and was, to say the least, a little agitated with the situation and decided then to change the approach to how I save my notes and share my thoughts.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>