<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Powershell on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in Powershell on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 15:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuring the Web Application Firewall with PowerShell.</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/configuring-the-web-application-firewall-with-powershell./</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/configuring-the-web-application-firewall-with-powershell./</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft Azure Application Gateway is a Layer 7 application delivery controller (ADC) offered as a service in Azure. It provides load balancing, SSL termination, end-to-end SSL, URL path-based routing, and basic web application firewall (WAF) functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working with the WAF, I usually build a basic configuration in the Portal before exporting the ARM JSON, which, then becomes my primary method to working on this service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Why JSON you may ask…&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updating Pester on Windows 10</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/updating-pester-on-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/updating-pester-on-windows-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spend the majority of my time working on my Windows machines, and for many scenarios, I find it difficult to complain. However, when Windows decides to dig the boot in and not co-operative; usually is when I grab my Mac Book and get the work done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, running aware from the problem rarely is a good fix for the issue; My latest battle has been Pester. The testing framework builds on Powershell, and by the grace of God, now shipped as part of the Windows 10 operating system.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>