<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building Azure with Code on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/series/building-azure-with-code/</link><description>Recent content in Building Azure with Code on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/series/building-azure-with-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bicep - Tags as Parameters</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/bicep-tags-as-parameters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/bicep-tags-as-parameters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploying infrastructure ARM Templates to Azure, but using Tags and their respective value as the parameter configuration settings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a post earlier, we look at using arm to lookup the value of tags&amp;rsquo; at both the Subscription and Resource Level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Bicep this is much easier to understand. This is the same lab configuration as in the original post, but this time to code should be a lot more readable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azure IaC - Function Keys</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/azure-iac-function-keys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/azure-iac-function-keys/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retrieve the Function Host Keys while deploying an ARM template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todays conundrum: As I deploy a new Function Application, I need a simple methodology to retrieve the Host Keys for the function application so that I validate the deployment has been successful; and potentially pass on the key to related services, for example API Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, I am leveraging templates, and will stay cloud native; this time depending on the functions Output ability to present the keys.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azure IaC - Appending Tags</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/azure-iac-appending-tags/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/azure-iac-appending-tags/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamically appending Tags to our ARM template with the union function&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todays conundrum: As I am leveraging templates, there will always be some standard tags I require to implement within the template, but I also require to provide additional tags as a parameter to be appended with the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My objective is to set up tags within an ARM template in accordance with good governance and the Cloud adoption framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>