<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure Edge Devices on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/categories/azure-edge-devices/</link><description>Recent content in Azure Edge Devices on Incredible Technology, Incredibly Simple</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/categories/azure-edge-devices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IoT - NodeRED on Arc-Enabled Edge</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/iot-nodered-on-arc-enabled-edge/</guid><description>Learn how to deploy a fully integrated Node-RED environment inside a K3s Kubernetes cluster on an Azure Arc-connected edge device. This guide walks you through namespace setup, persistent storage, service exposure, and secure access over SSH tunnels. Simulate MQTT and Modbus devices, visualize flows, and forward real-time telemetry to Azure MQ and OPC UA—all without opening firewall ports. Ideal for industrial IoT scenarios needing secure hybrid connectivity and local processing.</description></item><item><title>IoT - Azure IoT Operations</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/iot-azure-iot-operations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/iot-azure-iot-operations/</guid><description>&lt;p>An Azure Arc-enabled Kubernetes cluster is a prerequisite for deploying Azure IoT Operations. This article describes how to prepare a cluster before you deploy Azure IoT Operations. This article includes guidance for Ubuntu&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[!warning] ⚠️
Microsoft supports Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) Edge Essentials for deployments on Windows and K3s for deployments on Ubuntu. If you want to deploy Azure IoT Operations to a multi-node solution, use K3s on Ubuntu.
Starting from an Ubuntu server, which has be Arc Enabled, we can use this as a base for the Azure IoT Operations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IoT - Azure Arc Connected K3s</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/iot-azure-arc-connected-k3s/</guid><description>Transform your on-premises infrastructure into a cloud-integrated powerhouse by combining K3s Kubernetes with Azure Arc on an Ubuntu server. This guide walks you through every step—from deploying K3s and configuring user access to connecting your cluster to Azure Arc, enabling observability with Grafana, and integrating full-scale monitoring with Azure Monitor. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re building edge deployments or hybrid IoT solutions, this tutorial gives you a production-grade environment with the flexibility of the cloud and control of local resources.</description></item><item><title>Azure Arc enabling an Ubuntu Server</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/azure-arc-enabling-an-ubuntu-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 07:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/azure-arc-enabling-an-ubuntu-server/</guid><description>Discover how to transform a basic Ubuntu server into a fully Azure Arc-enabled edge device. This step-by-step guide walks you through onboarding a Linux server into Azure Arc, installing the hybrid agent, establishing secure remote access over web sockets, and enabling centralized management through the Azure Portal. Whether for IoT, hybrid cloud, or secure remote administration, this post equips you with the tools to bridge your edge environments seamlessly with Azure.</description></item><item><title>NodeMCU Pinouts</title><link>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/nodemcu-pinouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damianflynn.github.io/preview/posts/nodemcu-pinouts/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past year, I have been using a tiny board, known as the &lt;strong>NodeMCU&lt;/strong> which is essentially a developer board for a module know as the &lt;strong>ESP8266&lt;/strong>. The &lt;strong>NodeMCU&lt;/strong> is formed by an &lt;strong>ESP12E&lt;/strong>, which still has an &lt;strong>ESP8266EX&lt;/strong> inside it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="img-4d0d2e1c-NodeMCU_ESP12E.jpg" alt="Image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This device is really nice to work with, it is supplied preconfigured with a Micro USB input, for both programming and power.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The term NodeMCU usually refers to the firmware, while the board is called Devkit. NodeMCU Devkit 1.0 consists of an ESP-12E on a board, along with a voltage regulator, a USB interface.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>